The Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP) is a classic problem
in computer science and operations research. It involves finding
the shortest possible route that visits a list of
cities and returns to the origin point.
Let's assume we are an international salesman and need to visiting
clients all over the world. Our time is very expensive so
we need to find the most feasible and shortest way.
There are several ways to calculate or find the shortest way between
different point, cities in this case. This visualization is based on the
k nearest neighbors method. This algorithm involves the salesman starting at a
city and, for each step, visiting the nearest unvisited city until all
cities are visited. Essentially, the salesman looks at the 'k' closest cities
and selects the nearest one as the next stop. While this is
simple and intuitive, this heuristic does not guarantee the shortest overall route,
especially as 'k' is typically set to 1 for TSP, hence it's
often used for initial approximations.