Welcome back guys! Today, we're diving
into the Traveling Salesperson Problem.
Imagine we have a traveling salesperson - tasked
with selling your products in various cities.
This guy is Alex, a salesperson with a big challenge.
Alex has to sell products in various cities and wants to take
the shortest route to save time. But how does Alex figure out
the best route? Let's dive in and help Alex solve this puzzle.
Let's say he needs to visit 4 cities.
Sounds straightforward, right? What do you think happens if
we add one more city to Alex's route?
Of course, if we add more cities it get's more complex. So how
do you determine the shortest possible route that connects all these cities?
One approach is to try out every possible route. But here lies
the problem: Complexity! So, with every new city Alex adds to the
trip, the challenge of finding the shortest route grows significantly.
The Problem to find the shortest way between multiple points
is called the Traveling Salesperson Problem (TSP). Alex goal is
to keep the distance traveled as low as possible.
There are 2 main conditions: He needs to visit every city exactly
once, starting from a specific one and returning to the starting city.
To solve it, we'll think of each city as a point, or
'node', on a graph. The edges symbolize possible paths Alex can take.
The graph is complete, this means there's a direct
path from every city to every other city.
Also, in our model, the direct path between any two cities
is always the shortest. This means for two cities A and
B there is no path with an added point that is
shorter than the direct connection. adhering to the triangle inequality principle.
Our TSP is symmetric. It means the distance from city A
to B is identical to the distance from B to A.
This isn't really accurate in real life because
of conditions of the landscape or construction sites.
Thats why there is also a asymmetrical TSP.
The TSP is called asymmetrical if there are two edges between every node
and they don't have the same weight. As you can see the graph
is then directed. This is way more accurate to the real world, but
this is also more complex to solve then the symmetrical. In this video
we will only show you ways of solving the symmetrical TSP.
Let's take a look at how the TSP can be solved
To solve the TSP, we have two primary
approaches: the Optimal and the Approximation methods.
In the Optimal category, we have two prominent
algorithms: Brute Force and Branch and Bound.
Moving on to the Approximation approach, we'll explain
the algorithms Christofides and k nearest neighbors (kNN).
But let's start with the optimal solutions first.
The Brute Force method is a straightforward but time-consuming approach
to solve the TSP. It involves trying out all possible
orders in which the cities can be visited.
As the first step in our Brute-Force algorithm, we generate
all possible permutations of the cities. This means creating every
possible order in which the cities can be visited.
Then, For each generated permutation, we calculate the length of
the tour by summing the distances between the visited cities.
Now, we need to Identify the tour with the
shortest length among all the calculated tours. This is
the optimal solution to the Traveling Salesperson Problem.
We can calculate the number of possible paths as
the number of possible permutations of n elements when
each permutation is counted as a separate operation
For the example we've seen before we used
5 nodes, so we get 12 possible routes.
If we just increase the number of nodes
by 1, we already get 60 possible routes.
For 10 nodes, it's already 181440 potential shortest paths!!
So we got a factorial time complexity for the Brute Force algorithm.
Another way of solving the TSP is with the help of
the branch and bound method. Let's start with a simple TSP
example. Again we have a set of cities and need to
find the shortest possible route visiting each city exactly once.
The Branch-and-Bound method begins by constructing a tree of
all possibilities. First we need a Graph. Let's use
the same graph and start at node one.
Now we have to look at the next possible nodes. In this case we
have four options. We can go to node 2, 3, 4 or 5.
At the same time we can transform the graph on the right to
a tree with node one as the root. This tree will show all
the possible routes that the salesperson can use. As explained, starting with node
one the next possible nodes could be node 2, 3, 4 or 5.
This would be the first version of the tree. Now we
have to take a look at the next steps. Let's say
we choose node 2 as the second node to travel to.
Starting from node 2, the next options would be node 3, 4 or 5.
Now we can create the next step at the tree. Again the next
possible nodes to travel to would be node 3, 4 and 5.
Let's continue creating one possible route. We decide to
travel to node 5 as our next city.
Starting from node 5, there are two cities left that
have not been visited yet. Node 3 and 4.
Let's go back to the tree and add the last two options, node 3 and 4
This time we choose node 3 as the next city.
As you can see the last city, that we have not visited is city 4.
Let's also add node 4 in the tree. Now we have visited every city.
At the end we have to travel to the city where we started
the tour. Let's finish our route by traveling back to city 1.
Now we can also finish our route on the
tree by adding node 1 as our last node.
As you can see this is one possible route and
the tree is not complete. Let's create the complete tree.
This tree shows every possible route, if you start from node one. Here
we can now see that there are 24 possible routes to get to
the last node. But is you take a closer look at the first
and last route, you can see that the routes are identical, if we
have a symmetrical TSP. That means if we have a symmetrical TSP, as
in our example, we can ignore half of the routes.
Let's mark out the routes that we can ignore.
Here we can also visualize which route we took in the first example.
After having created a tree for every possible route, the branch and bound method
calculates the cost for every route and compares it to the best route so
far. If the cost of the current route is higher than the cost of
the best route so far, the current route will be discarded.
Let's take a look at an example. Lets say the algorithm calculated
our route first with the cost of 15. As it is the
first route, it is also the best route so far.
Next, the algorithm calculates the route on the left. The cost
of this route is 12. As this route is better than
the best route so far, it becomes the new best route.
Now the algorithm calculates the next route. In our
example it will be the seventh possible route.
In this route the algorithm realizes at the third node that the added
costs are at 14. Since the cost of the route till the third
node is already higher than the cost of the best route, the algorithm
can discard this route without calculating it untill the end.
This way of calculating the best route is applied to every
route. At the end the algorithm will have found the best
route. In this example it is the first one.
As explained, the algorithm calculates every possible route. But
as we have seen before, it can discard routes
that are worse than the best route.
That means the algorithm does not have to calculate every route
untill the end. Nevertheless, in the worst case the algorithm has
to calculate every possible route untill the end and the time
complexity is the same as the brute force method.
Thats it for the optimal solutions so far.
For the approximation methods, one problem is
to evaluate how good the algorithm performed.
So we need to point out how good our approximated solution is, compared to
the optimum. In some business cases there is a treshold given by the supervisor
so you don't need to know how near the solution is to the optimum
but in a theroetic case we want to know this. For large TSP to
determine the optimum is not economically sensible because of the complexity so we need
to find an other value to measure our solution.
So lets imagine we have these nodes as a tsp
and this is our approximated solution.
We take a look at all the weights and sum them up.
This is the value for our approximated solution.
But now we still don't now how good this is compared to the optimum.
For this we use the lower bound.
The lower bound is the value of the sum of
every weight of every edge in a minimum spanning tree.
So imagine we have these nodes from before.
We add the edges and their weights to the
nodes so we get our minimal spanning tree.
We take again a look at all the weights and sum them up.
This is the value of our lower bound.
Now we have a value which we can compare to
our approximated solution and we know how good it is!
Now we can continue with the approximated algorithms
In the following we will explain the christofides algorithm.
This is an approximated algorithm to solve the TSP.
This algorithm guarantees a solution that is at most
fifthy percent longer than the optimal round trip.
Let's take a look at the graph to visualize this algorithm.
First we will create a minimal spanning tree with every node.
Then we search for every node in the graph with
an odd degree, meaning an odd number of edges.
After finding all the nodes with an odd degree we need to find
a minimum perfect matching, so we need to find edges with minimum weight
for every node to get an even degree. Then we combine them to
obtain a multigraph in which every vertex has an even degree.
Since every vertex has an even degree, we can find an
Eulerian circuit in this graph. An Eulerian circuit is a path
that visits each edge exactly once. So as you can see
we go through our multigraph and note down every visited node.
The last step will be to convert the euleric circle into
a hamilton circle, so we have to delete all edges which
we have already seen before. In our case these are the
edges between 9 and 4. There we got our solution!
If we take a look at the time complexity of the Christofides algorithm
it is mainly determined by the step of finding a minimum perfect matching,
which is n to the third power. If time complexity is important, it
could be preferable than using Brute Force or Branch and Bound.
Our second approximation approach is k nearest neighbors (kNN).
We start at a specific city (any city can be the
starting point). Then we check the shortest path and add this
point to the tour. Same for the next node and so
on ... we repeat this until there is no unvisited node.
Finally, we draw a connection back to the starting point.
This is how it can look like with more
nodes, so more cities Alex has to visit.
For a dataset with n cities, the time complexity of applying kNN to
TSP is O of n squared. For kNN, time complexity is a bit
better compared to O of n to the power of 3 by using
Christofides. Both are faster than using Brute Force with a factorial time complexity,
but in most cases we won't find the optimal shortest path.
In this video, we showed you different methods to
solve the traveling salesperson problem. Every method has its
own advantages and disadvantages. The brute force algorithm is
the most accurate, but it is also the slowest.
The branch and bound method is faster, but
it is still not efficient for large graphs.
The Christofides algorithm is a heuristic algorithm, which means
it is not guaranteed to find the optimal solution,
but it is much faster than the previous solutions.
The k-nearest neighbor algorithm is also a heuristic algorithm. Even though
it is faster than the Christofides algorithm, results are often worse.
In the end depending on the size of the graph, you
have to decide which solution is best suited for your problem.
Thanks for joining us today! If you enjoyed the video
and learned something new, please give it a thumbs up
Don't forget to subscribe and hit the bell so you won't miss
our next adventure. Until next time, stay curious and take care. Bye!