Welcome back guys! Today, we're diving
into the Traveling Salesperson Problem.
Imagine we have a traveling salesperson - tasked
with selling your products in various cities.
This guy is Alex, a salesperson with a big challenge.
Alex has to sell products in various cities and wants to take
the shortest route to save time. But how does Alex figure out
the best route? Let's dive in and help Alex solve this puzzle.
Let's say he needs to visit 4 cities.
Sounds straightforward, right? What do you think happens if
we add one more city to Alex's route?
Of course, if we add more cities it get's more complex. So how
do you determine the shortest possible route that connects all these cities?
One approach is to try out every possible route. But here lies
the problem: Complexity! So, with every new city Alex adds to the
trip, the challenge of finding the shortest route grows significantly.
The Problem to find the shortest way between multiple points
is called the Traveling Salesperson Problem (TSP). Alex goal is
to keep the distance traveled as low as possible.
There are 2 main conditions: He needs to visit every city exactly
once, starting from a specific one and returning to the starting city.
To solve it, we'll think of each city as a point, or
'node', on a graph. The edges symbolize possible paths Alex can take.
It's complete, this means there's a direct path
from every city to every other city.
Our TSP is symmetric. It means the distance from city A
to B is identical to the distance from B to A.
Also, in our model, the direct path between any two cities
is always the shortest. This means for two cities A and
B there is no path with an added point that is
shorter than the direct connection. adhering to the triangle inequality principle.
With these rules in mind, let's explore
how Alex can find the shortest route.
To solve TSP, we have two primary
approaches: the Optimal and the Approximation methods.
In the Optimal category, we have two prominent
algorithms: Brute Force and Branch and Bound.
Moving on to the Approximation approach, we'll explain
the algorithms k nearest neighbors (kNN) and Christofides.
But let's start with the optimal solutions first.
The Brute Force method is a straightforward but time-consuming approach
to solve the TSP. It involves trying out all possible
orders in which the cities can be visited.
As the first step in our Brute-Force algorithm, we generate
all possible permutations of the cities. This means creating every
possible order in which the cities can be visited.
Then, For each generated permutation, we calculate the length of
the tour by summing the distances between the visited cities.
Now, we need to Identify the tour with the
shortest length among all the calculated tours. This is
the optimal solution to the Traveling Salesperson Problem.
We can calculate the number of possible paths as
the number of possible permutations of n elements when
each permutation is counted as a separate operation
For the example we've seen before we used
5 nodes, so we get 12 possible routes.
If we just increase the number of nodes
by 1, we already get 60 possible routes.
For 10 nodes, it's already 181440 potential shortest paths!!
This is because we got an exponential time complexity.
Our first approximation approach is k nearest neighbors (kNN).
We start at a specific city (any city can be the
starting point). Then we check the shortest path and add this
point to the tour. Same for the next node and so
on ... we repeat this until there is no unvisited node.
Finally, we draw a connection back to the starting point.
This is how it can look like with more
nodes so more cities Alex has to visit.
For a dataset with n cities, the time complexity of applying kNN to
TSP is O of n squared. Even though it's better than using Branch
and Bound in most cases we won't find the optimal shortest path.