Welcome back, folks! Today, we're diving
into the Traveling Salesperson Problem.
Imagine we have a traveling salesperson - tasked
with selling your products in various cities.
This guy is Alex, a salesperson with a big challenge.
Alex has to sell products in various cities and wants to take
the shortest route to save time. But how does Alex figure out
the best route? Let's dive in and help Alex solve this puzzle.
Let's say he needs to visit 4 cities.
Sounds straightforward, right? What do you think happens if
we add one more city to Alex's route?
Of course, if we add more cities it get's more complex. So how
do you determine the shortest possible route that connects all these cities?
One approach is to try out every possible route. But here lies
the problem: Complexity! So, with every new city Alex adds to the
trip, the challenge of finding the shortest route grows significantly.
The Problem to find the shortest way between multiple
points is called the Traveling Salesperson Problem (TSP)
To solve it, we'll think of each city as a point, or
'node', on a graph. The edges symbolize possible paths Alex can take.
It's complete, this means there's a direct path
from every city to every other city.
Our TSP is symmetric. It means the distance from city A
to B is identical to the distance from B to A.
Also, in our model, the direct path between any two cities
is always the shortest. This means for two cities A and
B there is no path with an added point that is
shorter than the direct connection. adhering to the triangle inequality principle.
With these rules in mind, let's explore
how Alex can find the shortest route.