Now we will explain the difference between
the symmetrical and asymmetrical Traveling Salesman Problem
This is the symmetrical one
This is the asymmetrical
Now we need to point out how to know
if our heristic result is near the optimum
In some business cases there is a treshold given by the supervisor
so you don't need to know how near the result is to
the optimum but in a theroetic case we want to know it
As we know to determine the optimum is not economically sensible so
we need to find an other value to measure our result
This value is the lower bound
The lower bound is the value of the sum from
every weight of edge in a minimum spanning tree.
This value is lower then the optimum but
in many cases very close to it.
So to gat an idea how good the heristic result is you need to
compare it to the lower bound which is easier to calculate then the optimum.