Welcome back guys! Today, we're diving
into the Traveling Salesperson Problem.
Imagine we have a traveling salesperson - tasked
with selling your products in various cities.
This guy is Alex, a salesperson with a big challenge.
Alex has to sell products in various cities and wants to take
the shortest route to save time. But how does Alex figure out
the best route? Let's dive in and help Alex solve this puzzle.
Let's say he needs to visit 4 cities.
Sounds straightforward, right? What do you think happens if
we add one more city to Alex's route?
Of course, if we add more cities it get's more complex. So how
do you determine the shortest possible route that connects all these cities?
One approach is to try out every possible route. But here lies
the problem: Complexity! So, with every new city Alex adds to the
trip, the challenge of finding the shortest route grows significantly.
The Problem to find the shortest way between multiple points is
called the Traveling Salesperson Problem (TSP). Alex goal is to keep
the distance traveled as low as possible. There are 2 main
conditions: He needs to visit every destination once. starting from a
particular one and returning to the same destination.