The Brute Force method is a straightforward but time-consuming approach to
solving the TSP. It involves trying out all possible orders (permutations)
in which the cities can be visited and calculating the length
of the tour for each of these orders. The shortest tour
found among these permutations is accepted as the solution.
First of all we generate all possible permutations
of the cities. This means creating all different
orders in which the cities can be visited.
Then, For each generated permutation, we calculate the length of
the tour by summing the distances between the visited cities.
Now, we need to Identify the tour with the shortest length
among all the calculated tours and the tour found with the
shortest length is the optimal solution to the TSP.