Another way of solving the TSP is with the help of
the branch and bound method. Let's start with a simple TSP
example. Again we have a set of cities and need to
find the shortest possible route visiting each city exactly once.
The Branch-and-Bound method begins by constructing a tree of
all possibilities. First we need a Graph. Let's use
the same graph and start at node one.
Now we have to look at the next possible nodes. In this case we
have four options. We can go to node 2, 3, 4 or 5.
At the same time we can tranform the graph on the right to
a tree with node one as the root. This tree will show all
the possible routes that the salesperson can use. As explained, starting with node
one the next possible nodes could be node 2, 3, 4 or 5.
This would be the first version of the tree. Now we
have to take a look at the next steps. Let's say
we choose node 2 as the second node to travel to.
Starting from node 2, the next options would be node 3, 4 or 5.
Now we can create the next step at the tree. Again the next
possible nodes to travel to would be node 3, 4 and 5.