In this video, we showed you different methods to
solve the traveling salesperson problem. Every method has its
own advantages and disadvantages. The brute force algorithm is
the most accurate, but it is also the slowest.
The branch and bound method is faster, but
it is still not efficient for large graphs.
The Christofides algorithm is a heuristic algorithm, which means
it is not guaranteed to find the optimal solution,
but it is much faster than the previous algorithms.
The k-nearest neighbor algorithm is also a heuristic algorithm, but
it is even faster than the Christofides algorithm. At the
end depending on the size of the graph, you have
to decide which algorithm is best suited for your problem.